{
    "id": "63627608cb7546058a1553ec26e98671",
    "title": "Simple, Compound Or Complex Sentence",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "04640b035b8b4f3aae8c9029a43db2c5",
            "title": "Simple, Complex Or Compound Sentence",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "We met rather few people who spoke English.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has a main clause and a subordinate adjective clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I have been on rather too many planes and trains recently.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has only one finite verb and hence it has only one clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "We drove right up to Helsinki in two days.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has only one finite verb and hence it has only one clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I don’t care how expensive it is.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has a main clause and a subordinate noun clause which acts as the object of the verb ‘don’t care’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Two minutes ago the child was fast asleep, but now he is wide awake.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has two coordinate clauses connected by the conjunction but.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "He is not tall enough to be a soldier.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has only one finite verb and hence it has only one clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I guess she just doesn’t respect you.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has a main clause and a subordinate noun clause which acts as the object of the verb ‘guess’.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I have got four sisters and each of them is quite different from the others.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has two coordinate clauses connected by the conjunction and.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "You can either come with me now or walk home.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has two coordinate clauses connected by the conjunction either…or.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "He will never leave home because he hasn’t got the courage to.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has a main clause and a subordinate adverb clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "When all else fails, read the user manual.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has a main clause and a subordinate adverb clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "It was Sam who paid for the drinks.",
                    "description": "The given sentence has a main clause and a subordinate adjective clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}